

# Nassim El Khantour

Multimedia Designer :: Art Director :: Web Developer

I am a French creative with an expertise in Web and Motion Design, but also proficiencies in development, 3D design, and illustration. An extended skill set I put at work in various projects for the past 6 years such as music videos, web apps, as well as audiovisual interactive setups. I am now looking to settle in Taiwan.

- Montréal, Canada
- (+33) 6 35 17 69 16
- nasselkh
- nassim.elkhantour@gmail.com
- elkhantour.com
- in linkedin.com/in/nassimelkhantour
- Bē behance.net/elkhantour

## **EDUCATION**

2019 - 2020

## Master's degree in Digital Art

DNSEP with summa cum laude.

ENSAD :: Nancy, France

2018 - 2019

## International exchange program (USA)

Web/Game Design, Illustration, and 3D Animation.

IUP :: Indiana (PA), USA

2015 - 2018

## Bachelor's degree in Digital Art

DNA (National Diploma of Art) with honors.

ENSAD :: Nancy, France

## **LANGUAGES**

French native English fluent

Mandarin intermediate

German basic

## **TECHNICALS**

Design

Photoshop, Illustrator, Premiere Pro, Figma, XD, After Effects, InDesign, Audition, Logic Pro X

Development

HTML, CSS, JS, Python, PHP SQL (basic), C# (basic)

3D production

Maya, ZBrush, Blender, Substance Painter, Unity

Video Mapping

TouchDesigner, Resolume Arena, MaxMSP

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE



### Lead Designer: Motion, Web & Print productions

.....

2022 - Present

Redbox Media Inc. :: Montréal, Canada

Design of visual and interactive content going from websites to print and motion design assets. Involved in agency's project management and team coordination.

- Production of motion design materials and sound design (google, meta, tiktoks ads, marketing collaterals, as well as product showcases...)
- Supervision and onboarding of junior designers, ensuring their work fit the established art directions.
- Design of websites and print assets.
- Branding and visual identity design.
- Videography and photo editing of the agency's events and venues.
- Providing web developers JS libraries to improve websites user experience (3D WebGL interactive content, SVG/SCSS/GSAP animations...)
- Setup and development of web apps and Adobe extensions to enhance the agency workflow.
- Collaborating with the Tech Lead to improve agency's technical stack.
- Team training: introducing production tools to management and development team.
- Managing agency's in-house projects (tasks scheduling, coordination of the production team).



#### Web Designer & Developer

2020 - 2022

Freelance :: Strasbourg, France

- Development and UX/UI design of LAOS: a web browser extension to improve Mandarin learning (React, Redux, OCR technology).
- Development and Web Design of an e-commerce coupled with a SQL client for products management.
- Development and UX/UI design of KINOJI: a website archiving various cinematographic content (NextJS, REST Api, MySQL).
- Art direction, background painting and animation for an animated shortmovie (music video).



#### Graphic & Multimedia designer

2016 - 2020

Independent contractor :: Nancy, France

Providing visuals for various cultural structures such as associations, music acts and soundsystems.

- Spatial organisation and scenography of various video-mapping installations.
- Art direction and animation for an animated short-movie (music video).
- 3D modelling, animation and compositing of more than a 100 visual samples made to be projected during events.
- Development and UI design of interactive audio-visual software (motion design, generative art).

## **AWARD**

#### Winner of Vibrations Urbaines Music Festival

2022

Le Grillen :: Ville de Colmar

English 1/2

# Nassim El Khantour

Multimedia Designer Art Director Web Developer

(+33) 6 35 17 69 16

nasselkh (LINE)

nassim.elkhantour@gmail.com

elkhantour.com

# PRESS & CURATED WORK

2021

PHILIP PENTACLE – ANIMAL CHAMBER APOCALYPSE BEAT [OCTOBER TONE]

Fedelab.fr

April 19th, 2021

Un nouveau clip très animé pour Philip Pentacle

Lalsace.fr

March 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2021

[NOUVEAUTÉ] PHILIP PENTACLE – ANIMAL CHAMBER APOCALYPSE BEAT

Mesenceintesfontdefaut.com

December 14th, 2020

Les clips de la semaine #39

Phenixwebtv.com

### **COMMUNITY SERVICES**

#### ...... Montrez-moi vos muscles Records

Strasbourg, France

Member and Visual Artist at Montrez-moi vos muscles music record (Video Jockey, visual live performances, music video).

90.12 WIUP

#### **WIUP radio station**

2018 - 2019

2019 - Present

Indiana (PA), USA

Member of the Music Team, selecting musics and helping the Web Team.

栖

## **HUMMUß GAFFER**

2016 - 2018

Nancy, France

Experiential art research collaborative project.

ECOTE

## **ENSAD BDE (students office)**

2016 - 2017

Nancy, France

Communication manager, designing events' communication media (posters, social media ads...)

## PERFORMANCES & EXHIBITIONS (SELECTION)

March 3<sup>rd</sup>, 2020

Maison Mimir fête ses 10 ans, with Philip Pentacle and Epic Schmetterling.

MOLODOÏ:: Strasbourg, France

December 5<sup>th</sup>, 2019

**CELEBRATION vernissage**, with Epic Schmetterling.

ENSAD :: Nancy, France

February 22<sup>nd</sup>, 2018

TECHNO, with ENSAD (BDE).

LNVRS club :: Nancy, France

October 6<sup>th</sup>, 2017

Ph pas neutre: Jaquarius, with CTL! soundsystem. LNVRS club:: Nancy, France

January 19th, 2017

ARK4-Artem, with Latitudes 5.4.

**CCAM**:: Vandoeuvre-les-Nancy, France

February 15th, 2020

**ART'ung Live**, with Philip Pentacle, Noyus and Epic Schmetterling.

Local ART'ung :: Willerhoff, France

April 14th, 2018

**Limedia Party #1**, as part of the **RING** festival, with CTL! soundsystem.

Théatre de la Manufacture :: Nancy, France

November 4th, 2017

CTL PARTY!, with CTL! soundsystem.

Ostra club :: Nancy, France

May 7<sup>th</sup>, 2017

Festival Moumouth Fest, with Epic Schmetterling.

Tanneries :: Dijon, France

December 8th, 2016

Freshmen homecoming, with ENSAD.

Appart club :: Nancy, France

#### **RELATED SKILLS**

Illustration Visual development Web design Photography Video editing Video compositing Concept art Motion graphic Sound design

English 2/2